#### Contact

BANGALORE, INDIA +919786436525 (Home) rhel7.vivek@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/dr-vivekyoganand-82a20264 (LinkedIn) scholar.google.fr/citations (Personal) vivekyoganand.github.io/ (Personal)

## Top Skills

Red Hat Certified Engineer (RHCE)

Python

IT Security Policies

## Languages

**English** 

Tamil

Kannada

#### Certifications

Oracle Cloud Infrastructure
Developer 2020 Certified Associate

Oracle Cloud Infrastructure 2019 Architect Associate

Infrastructure Foundations 2020 Associate

Verified International Academic Qualifications

### Honors-Awards

Best Physique - FORM III Cert.
- National Level participation Sportsmen Merit Quota.

Cross Country - FORM III Cert. - National Level participation - Sportsmen Merit Quota.

Tcsworld10k Procamrunning

IT Champions - 2017 "Technical Lead of the Quarter"

Tcsworld10k Procamrunning

## **Publications**

# Dr. Vivek Yoganand

PhD in Artificial Neural Network

Bengaluru

## Summary

I ♥# Linux

Working as Infra Dev Specialist in Cognizant,

Being part of different technology providers/organizations like Data Center services to a Value Added Distributor and a System integrator has helped in shaping up my career do address diverse markets, people and technology. Managing organizational IT compliance.

Strengths: IT Strategy, Team Building, Vendor Relationship Management and Negotiation skills.

Expert in UNIX flavors and other domains like Windows, Network, Security, VAPT, DevOps, Ansible, Satellite Server, Azure, AWS, Kuberneters, Docker, Podman.

Redhat Certified Engineer in Linux RHCE - 7.0

Extensively involved in,

- ★ Build the Infra and Testing Security Level policy
- ★ Deployment of various Application
- ★ Implementation of RBI Guidance
- ★ SOP/POA Review and Approval
- ★ Security Patch management & Version Controller

# Experience

Cognizant

Infra Dev Specialist

May 2020 - Present (4 months)

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

- ★ Azure DevOps
- ★ Kubernetes Development
- ★ Micro services Monitoring

Design of Accident Detection System Based On Vehicular Networks and Infrastructure Networks for Future Generation Vehicles.

Face detection approach from video with the aid of KPCM and improved neural network classifier

Multiview Face Tracking In Videos Using Clustering And Tracklet Linking Technique

Mobile Image Mining for Granite Quality Detection

Region Growing and Modified Neural Network Classifier Based Face Detection Technique from Video

#### **Patents**

Real time health care system for elderly people using fuzzy single input single output model

#### **IBM**

Subject Matter Expert - Employee ID: FRE26928 February 2020 - May 2020 (4 months)

Bengaluru Area, India

- ★ Team work and leadership skills with team of L1/L2 engineers to prepare them for L3 support activities in future.
- ★ Excellent working knowledge on the Filesystem and Logical volume management
- ★ Strong knowledge on RHEL administration
- ★ Strong Troubleshooting skills on RHEL.
- ★ Incident / Change / Problem management skill on Ticketing tools like service-now
- ★ Vendor management to concluding RCA and Corrective Action
- ★ Good experience on yum configurations and RHN network troubleshooting.
- ★ Involved in preparing to automate tasks with programming (Shell scripting) or configuration management tools (Ansilbe, puppet), etc. is preferred.
- ★ Experience in user administration / management
- ★ Knowledge and hands on experience on NAS and Samba Configuration.
- ★ Hands on experience on Version control systems.
- ★ Hands on experience on kickstart and pxe-boot installations.
- ★ Disk Administration with LVM Suite.
- ★ Expertise on file system management (Linux LVM, CFS, NFS, Samba)
- ★ Configuration of TCP/LAN Environment with NIS, NIS, NFS, DNS & DHCP
- ★ Good remote infrastructure troubleshooting skills.
- ★ Client interaction as per project needs
- ★ Excellent Customer handling skills
- ★ Excellent listening skills & ability to communicate clearly and fluently in English.
- ★ Good knowledge on AD and SSSD.

Ujjivan Small Finance Bank Limited 3 years 4 months

Patch Manager - IT Employee ID: UJJ19210 May 2018 - January 2020 (1 year 9 months) Karnataka, India

★★ Patch Manager - IT in Banking (Bangalore) Expert in Patching & Version Controller. Including Troubleshooting of various domains LINUX, AIX, SOLARIS, WINTEL, Middleware Patching, Database, Network, Firewall, Support Applications.

- ★★ All the approved patches deploying in all production servers N-1 on monthly basis as per OEM Releases and End-points.
- ★ Building the Infra and Testing Security Level Policy.
- ★ Deployment of various Applications & Troubleshooting in Cloud Infra.
- ★ Excellent troubleshooting skills both with hardware and software in patching environment.
- ★ Security Patch Management and Version Controller.
- ★ Work with engineering teams to understand infrastructure requirements, provide insight and directions to build and scale on micros service orchestration engine.
- ★ Establish and ensure infrastructure standards like security, reliability, availability, and scalability procedures are designed and maintained.
- ★ Essential responsibilities towards build and maintain practices for deployment, monitoring and operations for building infrastructure capability.
- ★ Ability to troubleshoot for complex software and infrastructure issues with RCA
- ★ Monitor applications and services within the environments, take actions to resolve issues and implement strategies to prevent future occurrences.
- ★ Active participant in agile process like Scrum Kanban etc.
- ★ Lead, design and provide infrastructure solutions across teams.
- ★ Responsible for implementation of infrastructure practices as part of Cl and CD.
- ★ Innovative thinking and introduce new features to operations of delivering microservice solutions.

Assistant Manager - IT Employee ID: UJJ19210 October 2016 - April 2018 (1 year 7 months) Karnataka, India

★★ Asst. Manager at Ujjivan Small Finance Bank Limited. Worked closely with Infra stability team and IT Security Team to ensure all security aspects as per the RBI ground guidelines. Expert in Linux, Solaris, AIX, Middleware patching & troubleshooting.

## MarkOne Technologies

Sr. System Engineer Employee ID: MT012 December 2012 - February 2016 (3 years 3 months)

Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India

- ★ Handling Servers 6000+ on Data Center Infrastructure.
- ★ Installation, Configuration and Troubleshooting of Red Hat Enterprise Linux in various flavors.

- ★ Basic Knowledge on running and writing Shell scripting.
- ★ Managing Process management, system Performance, Virtual memory, Disk & CPU utilization.
- ★ Creating the YUM server repository.
- ★ Data Compressing, Backup and recovery using tar command.
- ★ Configuring SAN Storage and managing through Disk management.
- ★ Monitoring the performance of the server and networks using CA-Spectrum and Nagios.
- ★ LVM Management, Skilled on Data Redundancy technology RAID (0, 1, 5) and User & Group
- administration.
- ★ Configuring DNS, DHCP, NFS, FTP, SAMBA, SSH, LDAP and Mail Server.
- ★ Deployment and maintenance of Linux systems and application software.
- ★ Administering software and updating packages.
- ★ Interact with vendors and applying Kernel, firmware, OS Patches.
- ★ Shell scripting for job automation and monitoring.
- ★ SAN & NAS LUN Management through Linux Native Multipath with File Systems (EXT4, NFS, XFS).
- ★ Running and Analysis of EMC Grabs for Heterogeneous host platforms.
- ★ Virtual Machine Implementation using technology Red Hat KVM and VMWare.
- ★ Created clones and templates of Virtual Machines and Migrating VM's using Vmotion.
- ★ System diagnostics, driving Root Cause Analysis (RCA) and Preventative action and SOP doc.
- ★ Administration of High Availability Cluster using Red Hat Cluster in Linux platform.
- ★ Taking care of CA-Service desk tickets (Incident & Request) related to various issues and addressing
- with adherence to SLA.
- ★ Worked on day to day trouble shooting for both User and Server issues.
- ★ Rotated 24/7 on-call support.

# Education

Anna University

Doctor of Philosophy - PhD, Artificial Neural Network, Computer Vision, Machine Learning · (2014 - 2019)

# Bharathiar University

Master of Business Administration - MBA, International

Business · (2011 - 2013)

## **SRM University**

M.Tech, Information Technology, Multimedia Technology · (2009 - 2011)

Jayam College of Engineering and Technology

B.E, Computer Science and Engineering · (2005 - 2009)